<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nexo blog</title><link>https://nexo.sh/</link><description>Recent content on nexo blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Oleg Pustovit</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 04:14:54 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nexo.sh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build Your Own HTTPS Tunnel in 300 Lines of Go</title><link>https://nexo.sh/posts/building-your-own-https-tunnel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nexo.sh/posts/building-your-own-https-tunnel/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>TL;DR: I built a lightweight, self-hosted HTTP tunnel that turns &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code> into a public &lt;strong>HTTPS&lt;/strong> URL. No paid plans, no secret black boxes. Just one Go binary, Caddy with wildcard TLS, and a $0/month Oracle Cloud VM. &lt;a href="https://github.com/nexo-tech/microtunnel">GitHub repo&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="why-i-built-it">Why I Built It&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My development workflow lives mostly on a free Oracle Cloud VM: SSH, Neovim, tmux—the usual hacker starter pack. I tried many ways to easily expose my local apps for testing webhooks, sharing demos, and collaborating with friends.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Set Up a Free Oracle Cloud VM for Web Development (2025 Guide)</title><link>https://nexo.sh/posts/setup-oracle-vm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nexo.sh/posts/setup-oracle-vm/</guid><description>&lt;img src="splash.jpg" alt="image title">&lt;p>As a web developer, having access to a persistent, virtual machine in the cloud is often useful for testing and development. While many cloud-based providers offer limited free tiers (e.g. AWS, GCP, or Azure), Oracle Cloud stands out by providing a true &amp;ldquo;always free&amp;rdquo; cloud VM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll look into setting up Oracle VM (under their always free tier). There are multiple advantages to using it instead of limited free offerings from services like AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Hugo Blog to GitHub Pages with Actions</title><link>https://nexo.sh/posts/setting-up-a-hugo-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nexo.sh/posts/setting-up-a-hugo-blog/</guid><description>&lt;img src="frame.jpg" alt="Image title">&lt;p>After years of building software and writing technical documentation, I decided to create a blog to share my experience and help others on similar journeys. This article walks through how I set up my technical blog, aimed at those new to blogging or Hugo.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="choosing-the-platform">Choosing the platform&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For me, it&amp;rsquo;s important to have as minimal a solution as possible. While building my own Markdown-to-HTML publishing script is an idea for the future, my immediate priority was to get the blog online quickly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title/><link>https://nexo.sh/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nexo.sh/privacy-policy/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="privacy-policy">&lt;strong>Privacy Policy&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Effective Date: 2025-04-25&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your privacy is important to me. This blog is a personal, non-commercial website focused on publishing technical content. I aim to maintain a privacy-respecting experience for all visitors, while also gaining insights to improve the content and performance of the site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This policy outlines what data is (and is not) collected when you visit this site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-information-i-collect">&lt;strong>1. Information I Collect&lt;/strong>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This site uses Google Analytics to collect anonymized usage data. This may include:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>