<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on nexo blog</title><link>https://nexo.sh/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on nexo blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Oleg Pustovit</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 13:43:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nexo.sh/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>In 2025, Apple still makes it hard to play your own MP3s, so I wrote my own app</title><link>https://nexo.sh/posts/why-i-built-a-native-mp3-player-in-swiftui/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 13:43:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nexo.sh/posts/why-i-built-a-native-mp3-player-in-swiftui/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>In 2025, playing your own &lt;strong>music on an iPhone is surprisingly hard&lt;/strong>, unless you pay Apple or navigate a maze of limitations. So I built my own player from scratch, with &lt;strong>full text search&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>iCloud support&lt;/strong>, and a &lt;strong>local-first experience&lt;/strong>. &lt;a href="https://github.com/nexo-tech/music-app">GitHub link&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="why-i-built-my-own-audio-player">Why I Built My Own Audio Player&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="frame_source.webp" alt="An image of a music app I&amp;rsquo;ve built">&lt;p>Like many people, I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up too many subscriptions, some through Apple (iCloud, Apple Music), others got lost in random platforms (like Netflix, which I forgot I was still paying for). I actually used Apple Music regularly (and previously Spotify), but the streaming turned out to be more convenience than necessity. With a curated local library, I didn&amp;rsquo;t lose much, just the lock-in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Microservices Are a Tax Your Startup Probably Can’t Afford</title><link>https://nexo.sh/posts/microservices-for-startups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 10:22:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nexo.sh/posts/microservices-for-startups/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Why splitting your codebase too early can quietly destroy your team’s velocity — and what to do instead&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;img src="frame.jpg" alt="microservice vs monolith">&lt;p>In a startup, &lt;strong>your survival depends on how quickly you can iterate, ship features, and deliver value to end-users&lt;/strong>. This is where the foundational architecture of your startup plays a big role; additionally, things like your tech stack and choice of programming language directly affect your team’s velocity. The wrong architecture, especially premature microservices, can substantially hurt productivity and contribute to missed goals in delivering software.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Build Your Own HTTPS Tunnel in 300 Lines of Go</title><link>https://nexo.sh/posts/building-your-own-https-tunnel/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nexo.sh/posts/building-your-own-https-tunnel/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>TL;DR: I built a lightweight, self-hosted HTTP tunnel that turns &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code> into a public &lt;strong>HTTPS&lt;/strong> URL. No paid plans, no secret black boxes. Just one Go binary, Caddy with wildcard TLS, and a $0/month Oracle Cloud VM. &lt;a href="https://github.com/nexo-tech/microtunnel">GitHub repo&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="why-i-built-it">Why I Built It&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My development workflow lives mostly on a free Oracle Cloud VM: SSH, Neovim, tmux—the usual hacker starter pack. I tried many ways to easily expose my local apps for testing webhooks, sharing demos, and collaborating with friends.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Set Up a Free Oracle Cloud VM for Web Development (2025 Guide)</title><link>https://nexo.sh/posts/setup-oracle-vm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nexo.sh/posts/setup-oracle-vm/</guid><description>&lt;img src="splash.jpg" alt="image title">&lt;p>As a web developer, having access to a persistent, virtual machine in the cloud is often useful for testing and development. While many cloud-based providers offer limited free tiers (e.g. AWS, GCP, or Azure), Oracle Cloud stands out by providing a true &amp;ldquo;always free&amp;rdquo; cloud VM.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll look into setting up Oracle VM (under their always free tier). There are multiple advantages to using it instead of limited free offerings from services like AWS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploying a Hugo Blog to GitHub Pages with Actions</title><link>https://nexo.sh/posts/setting-up-a-hugo-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 04:14:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://nexo.sh/posts/setting-up-a-hugo-blog/</guid><description>&lt;img src="frame.jpg" alt="Image title">&lt;p>After years of building software and writing technical documentation, I decided to create a blog to share my experience and help others on similar journeys. This article walks through how I set up my technical blog, aimed at those new to blogging or Hugo.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="choosing-the-platform">Choosing the platform&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For me, it&amp;rsquo;s important to have as minimal a solution as possible. While building my own Markdown-to-HTML publishing script is an idea for the future, my immediate priority was to get the blog online quickly.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>